Okay, so let's discuss the differences
then between a program, a portfolio,
and a project.
Now, first, let's talk about a program,
right?
A program are a group of related projects.
And that's something important to
understand.
This term here, that's why we've
underlined it.
It's related.
Programs are a group of related projects.
Not just a group of projects.
They have to be related in some way.
And different organizations,
different industries,
they're going to determine
what they mean by related.
There's no single definition of what we
mean by a related project.
The organization themselves are going to
determine what they mean by related.
But they have to be related in some way.
So programs are groups of related
projects.
Now, if you've got projects that are not
related, then they won't
be part of a program.
They will be part of a portfolio.
A portfolio are a group of programs and
projects, and plus other activities as
well, including ongoing operations that
are not necessarily related.
And that's a key thing about portfolios.
You've got all these activities going on
in your organisation.
They're part of a portfolio.
They're not necessarily related to one
another.
Whereas programs, they have to be related,
a group of related projects.
A one-off project would be part of a
portfolio.
And then other activities
such as ongoing operations,
as I mentioned, that would
also be part of a portfolio.
So a program then is
made up of many projects or
several projects, and
they all have to be related.
I remember a project is a
temporary endeavor undertaken
to create a unique
product service or result.
That's the definition of a project.
Sometimes projects are large.
We want to break them down to a little
sub-project.
And so, I mean, that's what sub-project
is.
It's just subdividing your project into,
you know, smaller projects, if you like.
Now, a very simple example of that
is shown here on this next slide, right?
So you have Project A and B that are
related to one another.
They would be part of this program,
part of Program 1.
You've got Projects E and F, they're
related to one another.
They are part of this program to A.
Right.
Then you have another project,
Project D, that's related to the program.
They're not really related
directly to either Project
E or F, but they're related
overall to this program.
And so they would be part of another
program.
So notice this program two includes a
program and a project.
But then there's a one-off project,
Project C.
It's not related to anything.
They would be part of a portfolio.
So all of these programs and projects are
part of a portfolio.
And then there's additional activities.
In this case, for example, ongoing
operations, right?
That would also be part of a portfolio.
So a portfolio is basically the strategic
activities for your organization.
Right.
So all of the activities combined could be
part of a portfolio.
Of course, you may have more than one
portfolio.
But the key about a portfolio is it
includes programs, projects, ongoing
operations, any other activities to meet
the same.
strategic direction of the organization,
whereas a program,
they have to be related.
The projects have to be related in a
program.